{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/28/elon-musk-says-trumps-spending-bill-undermines-the-work-doge-has-been-doing.html", "title": "Musk says Trump's big bill undermines DOGE; president counters with political reality", "body": "Elon Musk criticized President Donald Trump's signature spending bill that recently made it through a House vote, saying it counters the work he's been doing to reduce wasteful government spending.\n\nIn an interview to be aired June 1 on \"CBS Sunday Morning,\" the richest person in the world and the head of the Department of Government Efficiency advisory board said the \"big, beautiful bill\" will not help the nation's finances.\n\n\"I was, like, disappointed to see the massive spending bill, frankly, which increases the budget deficit, not just decrease it, and undermines the work that the DOGE team is doing,\" Musk said in a clip the program shared on social media platform X.\n\nTrump responded Wednesday to the critique from his top campaign donor.\n\n\n\n\"We had to get it through the House,\" Trump said of the massive spending bill. \"The House was, we have no Democrats\" who supported the package.\n\n\"I'm not happy about certain aspects of it,\" the president said, \"but I'm thrilled by other aspects of it. That's the way they go.\"\n\nThe sweeping One Big Beautiful Bill Act is projected to raise the federal budget deficit by $3.8 trillion over the next 10 years, according to the Congressional Budget Office, a nonpartisan agency that conducts economic analysis for Congress. The deficit is on track in 2025 to run close to $2 trillion, with the national debt now at $36.2 trillion.\n\n\"I think a bill can be big or it could be beautiful, but I don't know if it could be both,\" Musk said in the CBS clip.\n\nTrump and congressional Republicans counter that the bill reduces spending in key areas and will generate enough growth to compensate for the tax reductions. The legislation, though, is expected to face strong resistance in the Senate.\n\nFor his part, Musk has pulled back his DOGE work, saying he plans to focus on running his companies, which include X, Tesla and SpaceX. Musk had been a frequent presence in the White House since Trump's election.\n\n\"DOGE is just becoming the whipping boy for everything,\" Musk said in an interview Tuesday with The Washington Post. \"So, like, something bad would happen anywhere, and we would get blamed for it even if we had nothing to do with it.\"\n\nHouse Speaker Mike Johnson, R-La., on Wednesday praised DOGE and Musk's work.\n\n\"The House is eager and ready to act on DOGE's findings so we can deliver even more cuts to big government that President [Donald] Trump wants and the American people demand,\" Johnson wrote in a post on X.\n\nBefore the House can vote to approve the cuts, however, the White House needs to formally request permission to cancel some of the money that Congress set out for specific programs.\n\n\"When the White House sends its rescissions package to the House, we will act quickly by passing legislation to codify the cuts,\" said Johnson, using the term for White House requests not to spend money that Congress authorized.\n\nDespite Johnson's upbeat tone, many of Musk and DOGE's drastic cuts to government grant programs and the federal workforce have been met with resistance in Congress, including from Republicans whose districts have been hit by the cuts and mass layoffs.\n\nDOGE says it has saved $170 billion in taxpayer money since it began in January by targeting waste and redundancy in government.\n\nBut what counts as wasteful spending has proven to be a deeply divisive question.\n\nIn February and March alone, DOGE-related moves were responsible for some 275,000 government layoffs, according to Challenger, Gray & Christmas, a consultancy firm.\n\nMusk's work with Trump, and his frequently incendiary political rhetoric, have also inspired a backlash and widespread protests against his autos business, Tesla .\n\n\"People were burning Teslas. Why would you do that? That's really uncool,\" Musk told the Post.\n\n— CNBC's Erin Doherty and Lora Kolodny contributed.", "publish_ts": 1748390400000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "House", "sent_pos": 0.04030618816614151, "sent_neg": 0.7750979065895081, "ner_org": ["House", "CBS", "the Department of Government Efficiency", "DOGE", "X.\n\nTrump", "House", "House", "the Congressional Budget Office", "Congress", "CBS", "Senate", "DOGE", "the White House", "Trump", "DOGE", "The Washington Post", "House", "DOGE", "House", "DOGE", "House", "the White House", "Congress", "the White House", "House", "White House", "Congress", "DOGE", "Congress", "DOGE", "DOGE", "Challenger, Gray & Christmas", "Trump", "Post", "CNBC"], "ner_gpe": [], "ner": ["House", "CBS"], "topics": ["the", "and", "house", "musk", "that"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Elon Musk", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "June 1", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "CBS", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Morning", "label": "TIME"}, {"text": "the Department of Government Efficiency", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "DOGE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Musk", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "X.\n\nTrump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Wednesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Democrats", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "One", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "$3.8 trillion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "the next 10 years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the Congressional Budget Office", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Congress", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "close to $2 trillion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "$36.2 trillion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "Musk", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "CBS", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Republicans", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Senate", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Musk", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "DOGE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Tesla", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "the White House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "DOGE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Musk", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Tuesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "The Washington Post", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Mike Johnson", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Wednesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "DOGE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Musk", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "DOGE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "[Donald] Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "American", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Johnson", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the White House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Congress", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the White House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Johnson", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "White House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Congress", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Johnson", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "DOGE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Congress", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Republicans", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "DOGE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "$170 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "January", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "February", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "DOGE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "some 275,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "Challenger, Gray & Christmas", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Musk", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Tesla", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Teslas", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Post", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Erin Doherty", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Lora Kolodny", "label": "PERSON"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/27/consumer-confidence-for-may-was-much-stronger-than-expected-on-optimism-for-trade-deals.html", "title": "Consumer confidence for May was much stronger than expected on optimism for trade deals", "body": "Consumer optimism got a much-needed boost in May on hopes for trade peace between the U.S. and China, according to a survey Tuesday.\n\nThe Conference Board's Consumer Confidence Index leaped to 98.0, a 12.3-point increase from April and much better than the Dow Jones consensus estimate for 86.0.\n\nMuch of the positive sentiment, according to board officials, came from developments in the U.S.-China trade impasse, most notably President Donald Trump's halting of the most severe tariffs on May 12.\n\n\"The rebound was already visible before the May 12 US-China trade deal but gained momentum afterwards,\" said Stephanie Guichard, the Conference Board's senior economist for global indicators.\n\nMay's rebound followed five straight months of declines. Consumers and investors had grown sour on economic prospects amid the intensifying trade war that Trump has launched against U.S. global trading partners, with China a particular target.\n\nHowever, the two sides reached a truce in early May, marking the second major walk-back of Trump's so-called reciprocal tariffs since he levied them in his April 2 \"liberation day\" announcement.\n\nOther board sentiment indicators also increased.\n\nThe present situation index increased to 135.9, up 4.8 points, and the expectations index posted a major surge to 72.8, a 17.4-point gain. Investors also showed more optimism, with 44% now expecting stocks to be higher over the next 12 months, up 6.4 percentage points from April.\n\nViews on the labor market also improved, with 19.2% of respondents expecting more jobs to be available in the next six months, compared with 13.9% in April. At the same time, 26.6% expect fewer jobs, down from 32.4%. However, the level of respondents saying jobs were \"plentiful\" edged higher to just 31.8%, while those saying employment was \"hard to get\" increased to 18.6%, up 1.1 percentage points.\n\nSurvey officials said sentiment improved across age, income and political affiliation, though noting that the \"strongest improvements\" came from Republicans.", "publish_ts": 1748304000000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "The Conference Board's", "sent_pos": 0.8419243693351746, "sent_neg": 0.1393183022737503, "ner_org": ["The Conference Board's", "Dow Jones", "the Conference Board's", "Trump", "Trump"], "ner_gpe": ["U.S.", "China", "US", "China", "U.S.", "China"], "ner": ["The Conference Board's", "Dow Jones", "U.S.", "China"], "topics": ["the", "may", "and", "from", "trade"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "positive", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "May", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Tuesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "The Conference Board's", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "98.0", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "12.3", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Dow Jones", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "86.0", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "May 12", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "May 12", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "US", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Stephanie Guichard", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the Conference Board's", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "May", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "five straight months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "two", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "early May", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "second", "label": "ORDINAL"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "April 2", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "135.9", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "4.8", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "72.8", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "17.4", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "44%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the next 12 months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "6.4", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "19.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the next six months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "13.9%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "26.6%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "32.4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "just 31.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "18.6%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "1.1", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "Republicans", "label": "NORP"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/27/trump-hails-positive-steps-in-us-eu-trade-talks-as-markets-await-deal.html", "title": "Trump hails 'positive' step in U.S.-EU trade negotiations as markets hope for a deal", "body": "U.S. President Donald Trump gestures at the annual National Memorial Day Observance in the Memorial Amphitheater, at Arlington National Cemetery in Arlington, Virginia, U.S., May 26, 2025.\n\nU.S. President Donald Trump said Tuesday he was monitoring \"positive\" steps in trade talks with the European Union, after he agreed to delay a 50% tariff on goods from the bloc until July 9.\n\n\"I have just been informed that the E.U. has called to quickly establish meeting dates,\" Trump wrote in a post on the Truth Social platform.\n\n\"This is a positive event, and I hope that they will, FINALLY, like my same demand to China, open up the European Nations for Trade with the United States of America.\"\n\nTrump also said Tuesday that the EU had been \"slow walking\" in negotiations with the White House over a trade deal.\n\nThe sudden prospect of even greater tariffs on one of the U.S.' biggest trade partners rattled markets when it was threatened by Trump last Friday. In a post last week, Trump said discussions with the EU were \"going nowhere.\"\n\nHowever, sentiment turned positive on Tuesday amid hopes of a breakthrough. European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen said in a post on X over the weekend that the EU was \"ready to advance talks swiftly and decisively,\" while European Trade Commissioner Maros Sefcovic said Monday that he had \"good calls\" with U.S. Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick.\n\nEurope's regional Stoxx 600 index slightly extended gains after Trump's comments on Tuesday, last trading up 0.55% on the previous session, while U.S. markets opened broadly higher.\n\nThe 27-member alliance was hit with a 20% tariff on April 2 as part of Trump's \"reciprocal\" tariff strategy, which was then cut for almost all trading partners to 10% for 90 days. Concurrent U.S. duties on autos, steel and aluminum are also impacting the bloc's exporters.\n\nEU officials have repeatedly stressed that they want to reach a deal with the White House, but that this will not come at any cost. The European Commission, the EU's executive arm, earlier this month launched a consultation on tariff countermeasures targeting U.S. imports worth 95 billion euros ($107.4 billion) if a deal is not reached.\n\nCNBC has contacted the European Commission for comment.\n\nOn May 8, the U.S. unveiled the outline of a trade deal with the U.K., the first such agreement under the latest Trump administration, although businesses say they are awaiting further details. The deal maintains a 10% baseline tariff on U.K. imports to the U.S., suggesting other countries will face a similar rate at a minimum.\n\nTrump has generally struck a favorable tone toward the U.K. due to its more balanced trade relationship in goods with the U.S. He has accused the EU, however — with which it has a deficit in goods — of treating the U.S. unfairly. EU-U.S. trade is roughly balanced when accounting for both goods and services, according to EU figures.", "publish_ts": 1748304000000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "the European Union", "sent_pos": 0.8458401560783386, "sent_neg": 0.10436616837978363, "ner_org": ["the European Union", "the Truth Social", "FINALLY", "the European Nations for Trade", "Trump", "EU", "the White House", "Trump", "Trump", "EU", "European Commission", "EU", "European Trade", "Trump", "Trump", "EU", "the White House", "The European Commission", "EU", "CNBC", "the European Commission", "EU", "EU", "EU"], "ner_gpe": ["U.S.", "Arlington", "Virginia", "U.S.", "U.S.", "E.U.", "China", "the United States of America", "U.S.", "Leyen", "U.S.", "Stoxx", "U.S.", "U.S.", "U.S.", "U.S.", "U.K.", "U.K.", "U.S.", "U.K.", "U.S.", "U.S.", "U.S."], "ner": ["the European Union", "the Truth Social", "U.S.", "Arlington"], "topics": ["the", "trump", "with", "trade", "that"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "positive", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "annual", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "National Memorial Day Observance", "label": "EVENT"}, {"text": "Arlington National Cemetery", "label": "FAC"}, {"text": "Arlington", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Virginia", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "May 26, 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Tuesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the European Union", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "50%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "July 9", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "E.U.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the Truth Social", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "FINALLY", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "the European Nations for Trade", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the United States of America", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Tuesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "EU", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the White House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "one", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "last Friday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "last week", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "EU", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Tuesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "European Commission", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Ursula von der", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Leyen", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "the weekend", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "EU", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "European Trade", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Maros Sefcovic", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Monday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Howard Lutnick", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Europe", "label": "LOC"}, {"text": "Stoxx", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "600", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Tuesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "0.55%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "27", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "20%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "April 2", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "90 days", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "EU", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the White House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "The European Commission", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "EU", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "earlier this month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "95 billion euros", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "$107.4 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the European Commission", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "May 8", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.K.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "first", "label": "ORDINAL"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "U.K.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "U.K.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "EU", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "EU", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "EU", "label": "ORG"}], "relevance_label": "non_relevant", "relevance_score": 0.3}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/23/trump-greenlights-nippon-merger-with-us-steel.html", "title": "Trump clears Nippon merger with U.S. Steel", "body": "A water tower at the U.S. Steel Corp. Edgar Thomson Works steel mill in Braddock, Pennsylvania, on Sept. 4, 2024.\n\nPresident Donald Trump on Friday cleared the merger of U.S. Steel and Nippon Steel, after the Japanese steelmaker's previous bid to acquire its U.S. rival had been blocked on national security grounds.\n\n\"This will be a planned partnership between United States Steel and Nippon Steel, which will create at least 70,000 jobs, and add $14 Billion Dollars to the U.S. Economy,\" Trump said in a post on his social media platform Truth Social.\n\nU.S. Steel's headquarters will remain in Pittsburgh and the bulk of the investment will take place over the next 14 months, the president said. U.S. Steel shares surged more than 20% to close at $52.01 per share after Trump's announcement.\n\nPresident Joe Biden blocked Nippon Steel from purchasing U.S. Steel for $14.9 billion in January, citing national security concerns. Biden said at the time that the acquisition would create a risk to supply chains that are critical for the U.S.\n\nTrump, however, ordered a new review of the proposed acquisition in April, directing the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to determine \"whether further action in this matter may be appropriate.\"\n\nTrump said he would hold a rally at U.S. Steel in Pittsburgh on May 30.", "publish_ts": 1747958400000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "the U.S. Steel Corp.", "sent_pos": 0.2686615288257599, "sent_neg": 0.16547320783138275, "ner_org": ["the U.S. Steel Corp.", "U.S. Steel", "Nippon Steel", "United States Steel", "Nippon Steel", "the U.S. Economy", "U.S. Steel's", "U.S. Steel", "Trump", "Nippon Steel", "U.S. Steel", "Trump", "the Committee on Foreign Investment", "U.S. Steel"], "ner_gpe": ["Braddock", "Pennsylvania", "U.S.", "Truth Social", "Pittsburgh", "U.S.", "the United States", "Pittsburgh"], "ner": ["the U.S. Steel Corp.", "U.S. Steel", "Braddock", "Pennsylvania"], "topics": ["the", "steel", "trump", "and", "will"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "neutral", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "the U.S. Steel Corp.", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Edgar Thomson Works", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Braddock", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Pennsylvania", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Sept. 4, 2024", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Friday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S. Steel", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Nippon Steel", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Japanese", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "United States Steel", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Nippon Steel", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "at least 70,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "$14 Billion Dollars", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "the U.S. Economy", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Truth Social", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S. Steel's", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Pittsburgh", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "the next 14 months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S. Steel", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "more than 20%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "52.01", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Joe Biden", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Nippon Steel", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "U.S. Steel", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "$14.9 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "January", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Biden", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the Committee on Foreign Investment", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the United States", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "U.S. Steel", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Pittsburgh", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "May 30", "label": "DATE"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/16/the-low-end-consumer-is-about-to-feel-the-pinch-as-trump-restarts-student-loan-collections.html", "title": "The low-end consumer is about to feel the pinch as Trump restarts student loan collections", "body": "Wall Street is warning that the U.S. Department of Education's crack down on student loan repayments may take billions of dollars out of consumers' pockets and hit low income Americans particularly hard.\n\nThe department has restarted collections on defaulted student loans under President Donald Trump this month. For first time in around five years, borrowers who haven't kept up with their bills could see their wages taken or face other punishments.\n\nUsing a range of interest rates and lengths of repayment plans, JPMorgan estimated that disposable personal income could be collectively cut by between $3.1 billion and $8.5 billion every month due to collections, according to Murat Tasci, senior U.S. economist at the bank and a Cleveland Federal Reserve alum.\n\nIf that all surfaced in one quarter, collections on defaulted and seriously delinquent loans alone would slash between 0.7% and 1.8% from disposable personal income year-over-year, he said.\n\nThis policy change may strain consumers who are already stressed out by Trump's tariff plan and high prices from years of runaway inflation. These factors can help explain why closely followed consumer sentiment data compiled by the University of Michigan has been hitting some of its lowest levels in its seven-decade history in the past two months.\n\n\"You have a number of these pressure points rising,\" said Jeffrey Roach, chief economist at LPL Financial. \"Perhaps in aggregate, it's enough to quash some of these spending numbers.\"\n\nBank of America said this push to collect could particularly weigh on groups that are on more precarious financial footing. \"We believe resumption of student loan payments will have knock-on effects on broader consumer finances, most especially for the subprime consumer segment,\" Bank of America analyst Mihir Bhatia wrote to clients.", "publish_ts": 1747353600000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "the U.S. Department of Education's", "sent_pos": 0.014910402707755566, "sent_neg": 0.9634572267532349, "ner_org": ["the U.S. Department of Education's", "JPMorgan", "Murat Tasci", "Cleveland Federal Reserve", "Trump", "the University of Michigan", "LPL Financial", "Bank of America", "Bank of America"], "ner_gpe": ["U.S."], "ner": ["the U.S. Department of Education's", "JPMorgan", "U.S."], "topics": ["and", "the", "that", "student", "income"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "the U.S. Department of Education's", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "billions of dollars", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "Americans", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "this month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "first", "label": "ORDINAL"}, {"text": "around five years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "JPMorgan", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "between $3.1 billion and $8.5 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "Murat Tasci", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Cleveland Federal Reserve", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "one quarter", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "between 0.7% and 1.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "year-over-year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the University of Michigan", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "seven-decade", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the past two months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Jeffrey Roach", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "LPL Financial", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Bank of America", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Bank of America", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Mihir Bhatia", "label": "PERSON"}], "relevance_label": "non_relevant", "relevance_score": 0.3}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/16/consumer-sentiment-may-inflation-expectations-tariffs.html", "title": "Consumer sentiment slides to second-lowest on record as inflation expectations jump after tariffs", "body": "A woman walks in an aisle of a Walmart supermarket in Houston, Texas, on May 15, 2025.\n\nU.S. consumers are becoming increasingly worried that tariffs will lead to higher inflation, according to a University of Michigan survey released Friday.\n\nThe index of consumer sentiment dropped to 50.8, down from 52.2 in April, in the preliminary reading for May. That is the second-lowest reading on record, behind June 2022.\n\nThe outlook for price changes also moved in the wrong direction. Year-ahead inflation expectations rose to 7.3% from 6.5% last month, while long-term inflation expectations ticked up to 4.6% from 4.4%.\n\nHowever, the majority of the survey was completed before the U.S. and China announced a 90-day pause on most tariffs between the two countries. The trade situation appears to be a key factor weighing on consumer sentiment.\n\n\"Tariffs were spontaneously mentioned by nearly three-quarters of consumers, up from almost 60% in April; uncertainty over trade policy continues to dominate consumers' thinking about the economy,\" Joanne Hsu, director of the Surveys of Consumers, said in the release.\n\nInflation expectations are closely watched by investors and policymakers. Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell has said the central bank wants to make sure long-term inflation expectations do not rise because of tariffs before resuming rate cuts.\n\nEven with the pauses on import levies against China and other countries, the effective tariff rate for goods entering the United States is still significantly higher today than it was before President Donald Trump's inauguration in January. Economists on both sides of the aisle mostly agree that tariffs could lead to a short-term rise in prices, though the extent of that increase and whether it would fuel long-term inflation remains unclear.\n\nRecent inflation data has not shown a tariff bump, as both the consumer price index and producer price index for April came in below consensus estimates.\n\nA final consumer sentiment index for the month is slated to be released on May 30, and will likely be closely watched to see if the tariff pause led to an improvement in sentiment.", "publish_ts": 1747353600000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "Walmart", "sent_pos": 0.024174528196454048, "sent_neg": 0.9548659324645996, "ner_org": ["Walmart", "University of Michigan", "the Surveys of Consumers", "Federal Reserve"], "ner_gpe": ["Houston", "Texas", "U.S.", "U.S.", "China", "China", "the United States"], "ner": ["Walmart", "University of Michigan", "Houston", "Texas"], "topics": ["the", "inflation", "and", "tariffs", "for"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Walmart", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Houston", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Texas", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "May 15, 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "University of Michigan", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Friday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "50.8", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "52.2", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "May", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "second", "label": "ORDINAL"}, {"text": "June 2022", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Year-ahead", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "7.3%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "6.5%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "last month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "4.6%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "4.4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "90-day", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "two", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "nearly three-quarters", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "almost 60%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Joanne Hsu", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the Surveys of Consumers", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Federal Reserve", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Jerome Powell", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "the United States", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "today", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "January", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "May 30", "label": "DATE"}], "relevance_label": "short_term", "relevance_score": 0.8}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/15/jpmorgan-chase-ceo-jamie-dimon-says-recession-is-still-on-the-table-for-us-.html", "title": "JPMorgan Chase CEO Jamie Dimon says recession is still on the table for U.S.", "body": "Jamie Dimon, chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase & Co., speaks during the 2025 National Retirement Summit in Washington, DC, US, on Wednesday, March 12, 2025.\n\nWall Street titan Jamie Dimon said Thursday that a recession is still a serious possibility for the United States, even after the recent rollback of tariffs on China.\n\n\"If there's a recession, I don't know how big it will be or how long it will last. Hopefully we'll avoid it, but I wouldn't take it off the table at this point,\" the JPMorgan Chase CEO said in an interview with Bloomberg Television.\n\nSpecifically, Dimon said he would defer to his bank's economists, who put recession odds at close to a toss-up. Michael Feroli, the firm's chief U.S. economist, said in a note to clients on Tuesday that the recession outlook is \"still elevated, but now below 50%.\"\n\nDimon's comments come less than a week after the U.S. and China announced that they were sharply reducing tariffs on one another for 90 days. The U.S. has also implemented a 90-day pause for many tariffs on other nations.\n\nThursday's comments mark a change for Dimon, who said last month before the China truce that a recession was likely.\n\nHe also said there is still \"uncertainty\" on the tariff front but the pauses are a positive for the economy and market.\n\n\"I think the right thing to do is to back off some of that stuff and engage in conversation,\" Dimon said.\n\nHowever, even with the tariff pauses, the import taxes on goods entering the United States are now sharply higher than they were last year and could cause economic damage, according to Dimon.\n\n\"Even at this level, you see people holding back on investment and thinking through what they want to do,\" Dimon said.\n\n— CNBC's Michael Bloom contributed reporting.", "publish_ts": 1747267200000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "JPMorgan Chase & Co.", "sent_pos": 0.05550624057650566, "sent_neg": 0.8680066466331482, "ner_org": ["JPMorgan Chase & Co.", "National Retirement Summit", "the JPMorgan Chase", "Bloomberg Television", "CNBC"], "ner_gpe": ["Washington", "DC", "US", "the United States", "China", "U.S.", "U.S.", "China", "U.S.", "China", "the United States"], "ner": ["JPMorgan Chase & Co.", "National Retirement Summit", "Washington", "DC"], "topics": ["the", "dimon", "said", "that", "recession"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Jamie Dimon", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "JPMorgan Chase & Co.", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "National Retirement Summit", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Washington", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "DC", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "US", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Wednesday, March 12, 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Jamie Dimon", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Thursday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the United States", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "the JPMorgan Chase", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Bloomberg Television", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Dimon", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Michael Feroli", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Tuesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "below 50%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Dimon", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "less than a week", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "90 days", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "90-day", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Thursday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Dimon", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "last month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Dimon", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the United States", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "last year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Dimon", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Dimon", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Michael Bloom", "label": "PERSON"}], "relevance_label": "short_term", "relevance_score": 0.9}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/15/watch-fed-chair-jerome-powell-deliver-live-remarks-on-policy-review.html", "title": "Watch Fed Chair Jerome Powell deliver live remarks on policy review", "body": "[The stream is slated to start at 8:40 a.m. ET. Please refresh the page if you do not see a player above at that time.]\n\nFederal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell speaks Thursday morning to the Thomas Laubach Research Conference.\n\nThe topic of Powell's presentation will be the review the central bank is conducting this year of its policy framework. Conducted every five years, the framework review helps provide officials with a blueprint for monetary policy ahead.\n\nFollowing the last review, the Fed outlined a policy that became known as flexible average inflation targeting. The move was a stated intent to allow inflation to run slightly over the central bank's 2% target for a period of time in the interest of providing full and inclusive employment across the economy, including for race and gender.\n\nHowever, a year later inflation began to escalate, eventually hitting a 40-year high and forcing the Fed into a series of aggressive interest rate increases.\n\nRead more:\n\nFed holds rates steady as it notes rising uncertainty and stagflation risk\n\nPowell may have a hard time avoiding Trump's 'Too Late' label\n\nFed's Powell indicates tariffs could pose a challenge between controlling inflation, boosting growth\n\nSubscribe to CNBC on YouTube.", "publish_ts": 1747267200000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "the Thomas Laubach Research Conference", "sent_pos": 0.22674374282360077, "sent_neg": 0.03250277787446976, "ner_org": ["the Thomas Laubach Research Conference", "Fed", "Fed", "Fed", "Trump", "Fed", "CNBC"], "ner_gpe": ["YouTube"], "ner": ["the Thomas Laubach Research Conference", "Fed", "YouTube"], "topics": ["the", "powell", "fed", "inflation", "and"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "neutral", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "8:40 a.m.", "label": "TIME"}, {"text": "Jerome Powell", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Thursday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "morning", "label": "TIME"}, {"text": "the Thomas Laubach Research Conference", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Powell", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "this year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "every five years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Fed", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "a year later", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "40-year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Fed", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Fed", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Powell", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Fed", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Powell", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Subscribe", "label": "PRODUCT"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "YouTube", "label": "GPE"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/13/cpi-inflation-april-2025.html", "title": "Annual inflation rate hit 2.3% in April, less than expected and lowest since 2021", "body": "watch now\n\nInflation was slightly lower than expected in April as President Donald Trump's tariffs just began hitting the slowing U.S. economy, according to a Labor Department report Tuesday. The consumer price index, which measures the costs for a broad range of goods and services, rose a seasonally adjusted 0.2% for the month, putting the 12-month inflation rate at 2.3%, its lowest since February 2021, the Bureau of Labor Statistics said. The monthly reading was in line with the Dow Jones consensus estimate while the 12-month was a bit below the forecast for 2.4%. Excluding volatile food and energy prices, the core CPI also increased 0.2% for the month, while the year-over-year level was 2.8%. The forecast was for 0.3% and 2.8%, respectively.\n\nThe monthly readings were a bit higher than in March though price increases remain well off their highs of three years ago. Markets reacted little to the news, with stock futures pointing flat to slightly lower and Treasury yields mixed. \"Good news on inflation, and we need it given inflation shocks from tariffs are on their way,\" said Robert Frick, corporate economist at Navy Federal Credit Union. \"Non-tariffed goods are still in the pipeline, and perhaps some importers have absorbed their tariff costs for now.\" Shelter prices again were the main culprit in pushing up the inflation gauge. The category, which makes about one-third of the index weighting, increased 0.3% in April, accounting for more than half the overall move, according to the BLS.", "publish_ts": 1747094400000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "Labor Department", "sent_pos": 0.3707551658153534, "sent_neg": 0.5942747592926025, "ner_org": ["Labor Department", "the Bureau of Labor Statistics", "Dow Jones", "Treasury", "Navy Federal Credit Union", "BLS"], "ner_gpe": ["U.S."], "ner": ["Labor Department", "the Bureau of Labor Statistics", "U.S."], "topics": ["the", "for", "and", "inflation", "was"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Labor Department", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Tuesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "seasonally", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "0.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "12-month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.3%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "February 2021", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the Bureau of Labor Statistics", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "monthly", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Dow Jones", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "12-month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "0.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "0.3%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "2.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "monthly", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "three years ago", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Treasury", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Robert Frick", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Navy Federal Credit Union", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "about one-third", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "0.3%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "more than half", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "BLS", "label": "ORG"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/13/german-business-leaders-tell-new-government-its-time-to-deliver.html", "title": "'The Germans are back:' Business leaders tell government it's time to deliver", "body": "TEGERNSEE, Germany — Top German business leaders, economists and politicians descended onto a small, picturesque Bavarian town situated next to the iconic Tegernsee lake last week to share their hopes and discuss what's at stake for the new government. Buoyed by recent positive market sentiment for Europe's largest economy, attendees at the summit were united in their call for the new administration to step up and honour campaign promises. Any missteps would likely not be tolerated, with some business leaders warning the government cannot allow itself a \"lazy summer.\" Despite rain and low hanging clouds providing a somewhat dreary backdrop to the event, which has been dubbed the \"Davos of Germany,\" the promise of new beginnings enveloped the summit and the atmosphere was buzzing with excitement for potential changes the newly-appointed Chancellor Friedrich Merz could initiate.\n\nThe view across the Tegernsee from the Ludwig Erhard Summit Sophie Kiderlin, CNBC\n\nBig expectations for the government were commonplace, with concerns about Germany's struggling economy and recent political turmoil seemingly having faded into the background. The German DAX index is currently up over 18% since the beginning of this year, frequently hitting record highs in recent months. The German economy has however been in stagnation territory for over two years now, with tensions over economic, fiscal and budget policy in the previous ruling coalition and its eventual breakup continuing to weigh on expectations. \"There are very high hopes now on the new government,\" Patrick Trutwein, chief risk officer and chief operating officer at the IKB Deutsche Industriebank AG, said during a panel moderated by CNBC's Annette Weisbach. He said he was feeling positive about Germany's future considering the announcement of the major fiscal package enshrined in Germany's constitution, as well as further potential reforms ahead and \"an economy that's pretty robust and can build on its own ... productivity and competencies.\" Matthias Voelkel, CEO of Boerse Stuttgart Group, was among those feeling hopeful. \"If we look ahead and if they [the new government] do the right thing, I'm optimistic,\" he told CNBC. Audi CEO Gernot Döllner meanwhile said in a fireside chat that he was hopeful that the new government would \"send an impulse into the German economy.\" The mood was also upbeat in Germany's auto sector, which has long been struggling with competition from China, pressures from the transition to electric vehicles and has recently been hit by U.S. tariffs. \"The Germans are back,\" Hildegard Müller, president of the German Association of the Automotive Industry, told CNBC's Weisbach Friday. \"We are competitive,\" she added.\n\nA talk at the Ludwig Erhard Summit. Sophie Kiderlin, CNBC\n\nBut amid the positive buzz, it was clear that observers are keeping a close eye on the governments every move. \"This new government in Germany cannot allow itself a political lazy summer, I'm sorry, they've got to work and they've got to work hard,\" said Karl-Theodor zu Guttenberg, chairman of Spitzberg Partners and former German politician. Or as Veronika Grimm, member of the German Council of Economic Experts, told CNBC: \"A lot lies ahead for the government.\"\n\nOveral the message was clear: Germany needs to get its act together. Alexander Horn, general manager of Eli Lilly 's Germany arm — Lilly Germany — said the business strongly welcomes the new government's goals, but won't tolerate any caveats. \"Specifically we expect that the declarations of intent that are in the coalition agreement will be implemented quickly, speed plays an enormously big role,\" he said during a panel, according to a CNBC translation. Boerse Stuttgart Group's Voelkel indicated his optimism relied on action from the government, saying he was looking for moves towards \"less bureaucracy, less anti-growth regulation, more innovation and particularly strengthening investment.\"\n\nwatch now", "publish_ts": 1747094400000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "TEGERNSEE", "sent_pos": 0.9097896218299866, "sent_neg": 0.040716953575611115, "ner_org": ["TEGERNSEE", "Tegernsee", "the Ludwig Erhard Summit", "CNBC", "the IKB Deutsche Industriebank AG", "CNBC", "Boerse Stuttgart Group", "CNBC", "Audi", "the German Association of the Automotive Industry", "CNBC", "the Ludwig Erhard Summit", "CNBC", "Spitzberg Partners", "the German Council of Economic Experts", "CNBC", "Eli Lilly 's", "CNBC", "Boerse Stuttgart Group's"], "ner_gpe": ["Germany", "Tegernsee", "Germany", "Germany", "Germany", "Germany", "China", "U.S.", "Germany", "Germany", "Germany", "Lilly Germany"], "ner": ["TEGERNSEE", "Tegernsee", "Germany", "Tegernsee"], "topics": ["the", "and", "germany", "government", "for"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "positive", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "TEGERNSEE", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Bavarian", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Tegernsee", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "last week", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Europe", "label": "LOC"}, {"text": "summer", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the \"Davos of Germany", "label": "EVENT"}, {"text": "Friedrich Merz", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Tegernsee", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the Ludwig Erhard Summit", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Sophie Kiderlin", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "18%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the beginning of this year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "recent months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "two years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Patrick Trutwein", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the IKB Deutsche Industriebank AG", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Annette Weisbach", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Boerse Stuttgart Group", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Audi", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Döllner", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Germans", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Hildegard Müller", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the German Association of the Automotive Industry", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Weisbach", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Friday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the Ludwig Erhard Summit", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Sophie Kiderlin", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "summer", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Karl-Theodor", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "zu Guttenberg", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Spitzberg Partners", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Veronika Grimm", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the German Council of Economic Experts", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Alexander Horn", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Eli Lilly 's", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Lilly Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Boerse Stuttgart Group's", "label": "ORG"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/12/tariff-receipts-topped-16-billion-in-april-a-record-that-helped-cut-the-budget-deficit.html", "title": "Tariff receipts topped $16 billion in April, a record that helped cut the budget deficit", "body": "Shipping containers are seen at the port of Oakland, as trade tensions continued over U.S. tariffs with China, in Oakland, California, on May 12, 2025.\n\nReceipts from U.S. tariffs hit a record level in April as revenue from President Donald Trump's trade war started kicking in.\n\nCustoms duties totaled $16.3 billion for the month, some 86% above the $8.75 billion collected during March and more than double the $7.1 billion a year ago, the Treasury Department reported Monday.\n\nThat brought the year-to-date total for the duties up to $63.3 billion and more than 18% ahead of the same period in 2024. Trump instituted 10% across-the-board tariffs on U.S. imports starting April 2, which came on top of other select duties he had leveled previously.\n\nWhile the U.S. is still running a massive budget deficit, the influx in tariffs helped shave some of the imbalance for April, a month in which the Treasury generally runs a surplus because of the income tax filing deadline hitting mid-month.\n\nThe surplus totaled $258.4 billion for the month, up 23% from the same period a year ago. That cut the fiscal year-to-date total to $1.05 trillion, which is still 13% higher than a year ago.\n\nAlso on an annual basis, receipts rose 10% in April from 2024, while outlays declined 4%. Year to date, receipts are up 5%, while expenditures have risen 9%.\n\nHigh interest rates are still posing a budgetary burden. Net interest on the $36.2 trillion national debt totaled $89 billion in April, higher than every other category except Social Security. For the fiscal year, net interest has run to $579 billion, also second highest of any outlay.", "publish_ts": 1747008000000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "Customs", "sent_pos": 0.9318633675575256, "sent_neg": 0.047458503395318985, "ner_org": ["Customs", "the Treasury Department", "Trump", "Treasury", "Social Security"], "ner_gpe": ["Oakland", "U.S.", "China", "Oakland", "California", "U.S.", "U.S.", "U.S."], "ner": ["Customs", "the Treasury Department", "Oakland", "U.S."], "topics": ["the", "billion", "april", "for", "year"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "positive", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Oakland", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Oakland", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "California", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "May 12, 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Customs", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "$16.3 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "some 86%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "$8.75 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "$7.1 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "a year ago", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the Treasury Department", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Monday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "$63.3 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "2024", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "April 2", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Treasury", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "mid-month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "$258.4 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "23%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the same period a year ago", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the fiscal year-to-date", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "$1.05 trillion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "13%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "a year ago", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "annual", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "April from 2024", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Year to date", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "5%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "9%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "$36.2 trillion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "$89 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Social Security", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the fiscal year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "$579 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "second", "label": "ORDINAL"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/12/bessent-sees-tariff-agreement-as-progress-in-strategic-decoupling-with-china.html", "title": "Bessent sees tariff agreement as progress in 'strategic' decoupling with China", "body": "Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent said Monday that the trade agreement reached over the weekend represents another stage in the U.S. shaking its reliance on Chinese products.\n\nThough the U.S. \"decoupling\" itself from its need for cheap imports from China has been discussed for years, the process has been a slow one and unlikely to ever mean a complete break.\n\nHowever, Bessent said there are now specific elements of decoupling in place that are vital to U.S. interests. The U.S. imported nearly $440 billion in goods from China in 2024, running a $295.4 billion trade deficit.\n\n\"We do not want a generalized decoupling from China,\" he said during an interview on CNBC's \"Squawk Box.\" \"But what we do want is a decoupling for strategic necessities, which we were unable to obtain during Covid and we realized that efficient supply chains were not resilient supply chains.\"\n\nWhen the pandemic struck in 2020, demand in the U.S. shifted from one reliant more on services to a greater focus on goods. That meant greater difficulty in obtaining material for multiple products including big-ticket appliances and automobiles. The technology industry, with its reliance on semiconductors, was also hit. What followed was an inflation surge in the U.S. not seen in more than 40 years.\n\nThe details of the U.S.-China pact are still sketchy, but U.S. officials have said so-called reciprocal tariffs will be suspended though broad-based 10% duties will remain in effect.\n\n\"We are going to create our own steel. [Tariffs] protect our steel industry. They work on critical medicines, on semiconductors,\" Bessent said. \"We are doing that, and the reciprocal tariffs have nothing to do with the specific-industry tariffs.\"\n\nThe agreement between the two sides is essentially a 90-day pause that will see reciprocal duties halted though the 10% tariff as well as a 20% charge related to fentanyl remain in place.\n\nBessent expressed encouragement on the fentanyl issue in which Chinese officials \"are now serious about assisting the U.S. in stopping the flow of precursor drugs.\" Bessent did not indicate a specific date when the next round of talks will be held but indicated it should be in the next several weeks.", "publish_ts": 1747008000000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "Treasury", "sent_pos": 0.260608047246933, "sent_neg": 0.2722354233264923, "ner_org": ["Treasury", "Bessent", "CNBC", "U.S.-China", "Bessent"], "ner_gpe": ["U.S.", "U.S.", "China", "U.S.", "U.S.", "China", "China", "U.S.", "U.S.", "U.S.", "U.S."], "ner": ["Treasury", "Bessent", "U.S.", "U.S."], "topics": ["the", "that", "are", "bessent", "said"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "neutral", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Treasury", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Scott Bessent", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Monday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the weekend", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Chinese", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Bessent", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "nearly $440 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "2024", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "$295.4 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Squawk Box", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Covid", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "2020", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "one", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "more than 40 years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.-China", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Bessent", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "two", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "90-day", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "20%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Chinese", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "the next several weeks", "label": "DATE"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/09/germanys-economy-chief-reiche-sets-out-roadmap-to-end-turmoil.html", "title": "Germany’s new economy boss has a plan — and it starts with risk, speed and big bets", "body": "09 May 2025, Bavaria, Gmund Am Tegernsee: Katherina Reiche (CDU), Federal Minister for Economic Affairs and Energy, takes part in the Ludwig Erhard Summit. Representatives from business, politics, science and the media are taking part in the three-day summit. Photo: Sven Hoppe/dpa (Photo by Sven Hoppe/picture alliance via Getty Images) Picture Alliance | Picture Alliance | Getty Images\n\nGermany needs to take more risks and boost its stagnant economy with a decade of investment in infrastructure, German Minister for Economic Affairs and Energy Katherina Reiche said Friday. \"The next decade will be the decade of infrastructure investments in bridges, in energy infrastructure, in storage, in maritime infrastructure... telecommunication. And for this, we need speed. We need speed and investments, and we need private capital,\" Reiche told CNBC's Annette Weisbach on the sidelines of the Tegernsee summit. While 10% of investments could be taken care of with public money, the remaining 90% relied on the private sector, she said. The newly minted economy minister also addressed regulation coming from Brussels, warning that it could hinder companies from investments and start-ups from growing if it is too restrictive. Germany has had to learn that investments comes with risks \"and we have to kind of be open for taking more risks,\" she said.\n\nwatch now\n\nInitiating regulatory changes will in fact be one of the most important jobs for the new German government, Veronika Grimm, member of the German Council of Economic Experts, told CNBC on the sidelines of the Tegernsee summit. \"It will be important to adjust regulation, so removing or changing innovation-stifling regulation so that more is possible again in many areas of technology,\" she said in comments translated by CNBC. \"And then of course it is about improving the environment or businesses, making it more attractive so that we are competitive again,\" Grimm said.\n\nOn the edge of recession\n\nGermany's economy contracted slightly on an annual basis in both 2023 and 2024 and the quarterly gross domestic product has been flipping between growth and contraction for over two years now, just about managing to avoid a technical recession. Preliminary data for the first quarter of 2025 showed a 0.2% expansion. Forecasts do not suggest much of a reprieve from the sluggishness, with the now former German government last month saying it still expects the economy to stagnate this year. \"This country needs an economic turnaround. After two years of recessions the previous government had to announce again [a] zero growth year for 2025 and we really have to work on this. So on the top of the agenda is an investor booster,\" economy minister Reiche said. Lowering energy prices, stabilizing the security of energy supply and reducing bureaucracy were among the key points on the agenda, she added. This is despite a major fiscal U-turn announced earlier this year, which included changes to the country's long-standing debt rules to allow for additional defense spending and a 500-billion-euro ($562.4 billion) infrastructure package. Several of Germany's key industries are under pressure. The auto industry for example is dealing with stark competition from China and now faces tariffs, while issues in housebuilding and infrastructure have been linked to higher costs and bureaucratic hurdles. Trade is also a key pillar for the German economy and therefore uncertainty from U.S. President Donald Trump's changing tariff policies are weighing heavily on the outlook.", "publish_ts": 1746748800000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "CDU", "sent_pos": 0.35789331793785095, "sent_neg": 0.10370820760726929, "ner_org": ["CDU", "Energy", "the Ludwig Erhard Summit", "Getty Images", "Energy Katherina Reiche", "Reiche", "CNBC", "the German Council of Economic Experts", "CNBC", "CNBC", "Grimm"], "ner_gpe": ["Bavaria", "Germany", "Tegernsee", "Brussels", "Germany", "Tegernsee", "Germany", "Germany", "China", "U.S."], "ner": ["CDU", "Energy", "Bavaria", "Germany"], "topics": ["the", "and", "for", "from", "economy"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "neutral", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "09 May 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Bavaria", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Katherina Reiche", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "CDU", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Energy", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the Ludwig Erhard Summit", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "three-day", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Sven Hoppe", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Sven Hoppe", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Getty Images", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "a decade", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Energy Katherina Reiche", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Friday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "The next decade", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the decade", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Reiche", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Annette Weisbach", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Tegernsee", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the remaining 90%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Brussels", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Veronika Grimm", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the German Council of Economic Experts", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Tegernsee", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Grimm", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "annual", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "both 2023 and 2024", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "quarterly", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "two years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the first quarter of 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "0.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "last month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "this year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "two years", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Reiche", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "earlier this year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "500-billion-euro", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "$562.4 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}], "relevance_label": "short_term", "relevance_score": 0.8}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/08/andrew-bailey-on-why-uk-us-trade-deal-wont-end-uncertainty-.html", "title": "Why the Bank of England governor thinks uncertainty is here to stay despite a trade deal", "body": "Bank of England Governor Andrew Bailey told CNBC on Thursday that the U.K. was heading for more economic uncertainty, despite the country being the first to strike a trade agreement with the U.S. under President Donald Trump's controversial tariff regime.\n\n\"The tariff and trade situation has injected more uncertainty into the situation... There's more uncertainty now than there was in the past,\" Bailey told CNBC in an interview.\n\n\"A U.K.-U.S. trade agreement is very welcome in that sense, very welcome. But the U.K. is a very open economy,\" he continued.\n\nThat means that the impact from tariffs on the U.K. economy comes not just from its own trade relationship with Washington, but also from those of the U.S. and the rest of the world, he said.\n\n\"I hope that what we're seeing on the U.K.-U.S. trade side will be the first of many, and it will be repeated by a whole series of trade agreements, but we have to see that happen of course, and where it actually ends up.\"\n\n\"Because, of course, we are looking at tariff levels that are probably higher than they were beforehand.\"", "publish_ts": 1746662400000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "Bank of England", "sent_pos": 0.30978792905807495, "sent_neg": 0.2793548107147217, "ner_org": ["Bank of England", "CNBC", "CNBC"], "ner_gpe": ["U.K.", "U.S.", "U.K.", "U.K.", "Washington", "U.S."], "ner": ["Bank of England", "CNBC", "U.K.", "U.S."], "topics": ["the", "that", "trade", "and", "more"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "neutral", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Bank of England", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Andrew Bailey", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Thursday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.K.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "first", "label": "ORDINAL"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Bailey", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "U.K.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.K.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Washington", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "first", "label": "ORDINAL"}], "relevance_label": "non_relevant", "relevance_score": 0.3}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/05/china-risks-deeper-deflation-by-diverting-exports-to-domestic-market.html", "title": "China risks a spiral into deeper deflation as it diverts U.S.-bound exports to domestic market", "body": "SHENZHEN, CHINA - APRIL 12: A woman checks her smartphone while walking past a busy intersection in front of a Sam's Club membership store and a McDonald's restaurant on April 12, 2025 in Shenzhen, China.\n\nAs sky-high tariffs kill U.S. orders for Chinese goods, the country has been striving to help exporters divert sales to the domestic market — a move that threatens to drive the world's second-largest economy into deeper deflation.\n\nLocal Chinese governments and major businesses have voiced support to help tariff-hit exporters redirect their products to the domestic market for sale. JD.com , Tencent and Douyin, TikTok's sister app in China, are among the e-commerce giants promoting sales of these goods to Chinese consumers.\n\nSheng Qiuping, vice commerce minister, in a statement last month described China's vast domestic market as a crucial buffer for exporters in weathering external shocks, urging local authorities to coordinate efforts in stabilizing exports and boosting consumption.\n\n\"The side effect is a ferocious price war among Chinese firms,\" said Yingke Zhou, senior China economist at Barclays Bank.\n\nJD.com, for instance, has pledged 200 billion yuan ($28 billion) to help exporters and has set up a dedicated section on its platform for goods originally intended for U.S. buyers, with discounts of up to 55%.\n\nAn influx of discounted goods intended for the U.S. market would also erode companies' profitability, which in turn would weigh on employment, Zhou said. Uncertain job prospects and worries over income stability have already been contributing to weak consumer demand.\n\nAfter hovering just above zero in 2023 and 2024, the consumer price index slipped into negative territory, declining for two straight months in February and March. The producer price index fell for a 29th consecutive month in March, down 2.5% from a year earlier, to clock its steepest decline in four months.\n\nAs the trade war knocks down export orders, deflation in China's wholesale prices will likely deepen to 2.8% in April, from 2.5% in March, according to a team of economists at Morgan Stanley. \"We believe the tariff impact will be the most acute this quarter, as many exporters have halted their production and shipments to the U.S.\"\n\nFor the full year, Shan Hui, chief China economist at Goldman Sachs, expects China's CPI to fall to 0%, from a 0.2% year-on-year growth in 2024, and PPI to decline by 1.6% from a 2.2% drop last year.", "publish_ts": 1746403200000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "McDonald", "sent_pos": 0.009493759833276272, "sent_neg": 0.9749565720558167, "ner_org": ["McDonald", "Tencent", "TikTok", "Barclays Bank", "Morgan Stanley", "Goldman Sachs"], "ner_gpe": ["SHENZHEN", "CHINA", "Shenzhen", "China", "U.S.", "China", "China", "China", "U.S.", "U.S.", "China", "U.S.", "China", "China"], "ner": ["McDonald", "Tencent", "SHENZHEN", "CHINA"], "topics": ["the", "and", "for", "china", "exporters"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "SHENZHEN", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "CHINA", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "12", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "McDonald", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "April 12, 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Shenzhen", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Chinese", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "second", "label": "ORDINAL"}, {"text": "Chinese", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Tencent", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "TikTok", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Chinese", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Sheng Qiuping", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "last month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Chinese", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "Yingke Zhou", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Barclays Bank", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "200 billion yuan", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "$28 billion", "label": "MONEY"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "up to 55%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Zhou", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "just above zero", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "2023", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2024", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "two straight months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "February and March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "a 29th consecutive month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.5%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "a year earlier", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "four months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "2.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.5%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Morgan Stanley", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "this quarter", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "the full year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Shan Hui", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Goldman Sachs", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "China", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "0%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "0.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "2024", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "1.6%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "2.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "last year", "label": "DATE"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/02/jobs-report-april-2025.html", "title": "U.S. payroll growth totals 177,000 in April, defying expectations", "body": "Nonfarm payrolls increased a seasonally adjusted 177,000 for the month, slightly below the downwardly revised 185,000 in March but above the Dow Jones estimate for 133,000, the Bureau of Labor Statistics reported Friday.\n\nJob growth was stronger than expected in April despite worries over the impact of President Donald Trump 's blanket tariffs against U.S. trading partners.\n\nA broader unemployment gauge that includes discouraged workers and those holding part-time jobs for economic reasons, or the underemployed, edged lower to 7.8%. The labor force participation rate ticked higher to 62.6%.\n\nThe unemployment rate held at 4.2%, as expected, indicating that the labor market is holding relatively stable. The survey of households, which is used to calculate the jobless rate, showed an even stronger gain, with an increase of 436,000 in those who reported holding jobs on the month.\n\nStock market futures rose following the release as did Treasury yields.\n\n\"We can push recession concerns to another month. Job numbers remain very strong, suggesting there was an impressive degree of resilience in the economy in play before the tariff shock,\" said Seema Shah, chief global strategist at Principal Asset Management. \"The economy will weaken in the coming months but, with this underlying momentum, the U.S. has a decent chance of averting recession if it can step back from the tariff brink in time.\"\n\nThe report comes amid an uncertain climate in which Trump kicked off April by slapping \"liberation day\" 10% across-the-board tariffs on U.S. imports, and threatened a menu of other \"reciprocal\" duties on dozens of other nations.\n\nHowever, Trump later decided to put a 90-day hold on the reciprocal tariffs pending ongoing negotiations. In recent days, White House officials have indicated that deals with some of the impacted nations are forthcoming, though there have been no official announcements.\n\nThe strong report led traders to push out expectations for an interest rate cut until July, according to the CME Group's FedWatch gauge of futures pricing.\n\nHealth care continued to be a leader in job creation, adding 51,000 jobs. Other sectors posting gains included transportation and warehousing (29,000), financial activities (14,000), and social assistance.\n\nThe federal government reported a loss of 9,000 jobs on the month amid Trump's efforts, led by Elon Musk and the Department of Government Efficiency, to trim payrolls in the public sector. Federal government jobs have declined by just 26,000 since January, as employees furloughed but still receiving severance are not counted as unemployed, according to the BLS.\n\nManufacturing saw a slight loss of 1,000 jobs as well.\n\n\"This first jobs report post-Liberation Day is much too soon for the impacts of tariffs to show up,\" said Daniel Zhao, lead economist at job review site Glassdoor. \"Even May may still be too early as businesses work down inventories. But today's report does set the benchmark against which we'll measure the tariff impacts.\"\n\nOn the wage side, average hourly earnings rose just 0.2% for the month, below the 0.3% forecast, while the annual rate of 3.8% also was 0.1 percentage point less than expected and the lowest since July 2024.", "publish_ts": 1746144000000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "Nonfarm", "sent_pos": 0.4785214066505432, "sent_neg": 0.49542000889778137, "ner_org": ["Nonfarm", "Dow Jones", "the Bureau of Labor Statistics", "Treasury", "Principal Asset Management", "Trump", "Trump", "White House", "the CME Group's", "FedWatch", "Trump", "the Department of Government Efficiency", "BLS", "Glassdoor"], "ner_gpe": ["U.S.", "U.S.", "U.S."], "ner": ["Nonfarm", "Dow Jones", "U.S.", "U.S."], "topics": ["the", "jobs", "for", "and", "month"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Nonfarm", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "177,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "185,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Dow Jones", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "133,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "the Bureau of Labor Statistics", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Friday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "7.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "62.6%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "4.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "436,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Treasury", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "another month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Seema Shah", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Principal Asset Management", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the coming months", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "dozens", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "90-day", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "recent days", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "White House", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "July", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the CME Group's", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "FedWatch", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "51,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "29,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "14,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "9,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Elon Musk", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the Department of Government Efficiency", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "just 26,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "January", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "BLS", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "1,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "first", "label": "ORDINAL"}, {"text": "post-Liberation Day", "label": "EVENT"}, {"text": "Daniel Zhao", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Glassdoor", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "May", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "today", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "hourly", "label": "TIME"}, {"text": "just 0.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "0.3%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "annual", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "3.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "0.1", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "July 2024", "label": "DATE"}], "relevance_label": "short_term", "relevance_score": 0.8}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/02/euro-zone-inflation-april-2025.html", "title": "Euro zone inflation unchanged at 2.2% in April, leaving path open for further ECB interest rate cuts", "body": "Shoppers buy fresh vegetables, fruit, and herbs at an outdoor produce market under green-striped canopies in Regensburg, Upper Palatinate, Bavaria, Germany, on April 19, 2025.\n\nEuro zone inflation was unchanged at 2.2% in April, missing expectations for a move lower, flash data from statistics agency Eurostat showed Friday.\n\nEconomists polled by Reuters had been expecting the reading to come in at 2.1% in April compared to March's 2.2% as inflation has been easing back towards the European Central Bank's 2% target.\n\nCore inflation, which excludes more volatile food, energy, alcohol and tobacco prices, accelerated to 2.7% from March's 2.4%. The closely-watched services inflation print also picked up again, coming in at 3.9% compared to the previous 3.5% reading.\n\nThe euro was higher against the U.S. dollar and the British pound following the data release. Bond yields were little changed, with the yield on 10-year German bonds continuing to trade around 3 basis points higher.\n\nThe increase in services inflation was likely \"driven mainly by Easter timing effects,\" Franziska Palmas, senior Europe economist at Capital Economics, said in a note. These effects would reverse in the coming month, she added, suggesting that this left the door open for further interest rate cuts from the European Central Bank.\n\n\"We think the services rate will decline significantly in the rest of this year as US tariffs weigh on activity and the labour market continues to weaken,\" Palmas added.\n\nMichael Field, chief equity strategist at Morningstar, meanwhile urged caution, saying tariff uncertainty meant \"any level of comfort we have here is precarious.\" A further escalation of tariff tensions would mean a pick-up of inflation in Europe, he said.\n\nField added that further ECB rate cuts were still on the table. \"This relatively low level of headline inflation keeps the pressure off the ECB, who can in turn lower interest rates further,\" he said.\n\nECB President Christine Lagarde told CNBC last week that \"we're heading towards our [inflation] target in the course of 2025, so that disinflationary process is so much on track that we are nearing completion.\"\n\nLagarde and other policymakers last week warned the picture for inflation was less clear in the medium-term, with factors such as potential retaliation countermeasures from Europe against U.S. tariffs and fiscal shifts like Germany's major infrastructure package coming into play.\n\nLagarde said the ECB would be \"data dependent to the extreme,\" when making interest rate decisions. The central bank last cut interest rates last month, taking its key rate — the deposit facility rate — to 2.25%, down from highs of 4% in mid-2023.", "publish_ts": 1746144000000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "Upper Palatinate", "sent_pos": 0.1784946620464325, "sent_neg": 0.7968843579292297, "ner_org": ["Upper Palatinate", "Eurostat", "Reuters", "the European Central Bank's", "Capital Economics", "the European Central Bank", "Morningstar", "ECB", "CNBC", "ECB"], "ner_gpe": ["Regensburg", "Bavaria", "Germany", "U.S.", "US", "Lagarde", "U.S.", "Germany", "Lagarde"], "ner": ["Upper Palatinate", "Eurostat", "Regensburg", "Bavaria"], "topics": ["the", "inflation", "and", "rate", "from"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Regensburg", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Upper Palatinate", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Bavaria", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "April 19, 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Eurostat", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Friday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Reuters", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "2.1%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the European Central Bank's", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "2.7%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "3.9%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "3.5%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "British", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "10-year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "German", "label": "NORP"}, {"text": "3", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "Easter", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Franziska Palmas", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Europe", "label": "LOC"}, {"text": "Capital Economics", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the coming month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the European Central Bank", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "this year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "US", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Palmas", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Michael Field", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Morningstar", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Europe", "label": "LOC"}, {"text": "ECB", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Christine Lagarde", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "CNBC", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "last week", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Lagarde", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "last week", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Europe", "label": "LOC"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Germany", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Lagarde", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "ECB", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "last month", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "2.25%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "mid-2023", "label": "DATE"}], "relevance_label": "long_term", "relevance_score": 0.85}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/01/jobs-report-friday-to-provide-important-clues-on-where-the-economy-is-heading-.html", "title": "Jobs report Friday to provide important clues on where the economy is heading", "body": "Steven Chechette (C) speaks with a recruiter at the KeySource booth at the Mega JobNewsUSA South Florida Job Fair held in the Amerant Bank Arena on April 30, 2025, in Sunrise, Florida.\n\nClues on whether the U.S. economy is merely in a temporary tariff-induced funk or a more damaging longer-turn downtrend should come Friday when the Labor Department releases the April jobs report.\n\nEconomists expect nonfarm payrolls to post an increase of 133,000, which would be a steep slide from the 228,000 in March, according to the Dow Jones consensus. However, it would be only slightly below the 152,000 average for the first three months of the year and likely would be enough to hold the unemployment rate around 4.2%.\n\nBut a downside surprise could be perilous considering the recent spate of bad economic news and the prevailing angst over the way President Donald Trump is implementing tariffs against U.S. trading partners.\n\n\"If it's around 150,000 give or take, I think all will be forgiven,\" said Mark Zandi, chief economist at Moody's Analytics. \"So I think we'll end the week feeling OK, not great, but OK. Things aren't falling apart.\"\n\nHowever, Zandi and other economists say financial markets may want to brace for disappointment. Specifically, he has his eye on anything less than 100,000 for payrolls growth, which he expects would cause the dour economic feelings to take over.\n\n\"If the number's 100,000 or anything south of that, then I think I'd watch out,\" he said. \"Then all the other data will take on greater importance, and people will be marking down their expectations. That could be a tough day in the markets.\"", "publish_ts": 1746057600000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "KeySource", "sent_pos": 0.029310151934623718, "sent_neg": 0.957250714302063, "ner_org": ["KeySource", "the Amerant Bank Arena", "the Labor Department", "Dow Jones", "Moody's Analytics"], "ner_gpe": ["Sunrise", "Florida", "U.S.", "U.S.", "Zandi"], "ner": ["KeySource", "the Amerant Bank Arena", "Sunrise", "Florida"], "topics": ["the", "would", "and", "for", "take"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "Steven Chechette", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "KeySource", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Mega", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the Amerant Bank Arena", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "April 30, 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Sunrise", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Florida", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Friday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the Labor Department", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "133,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "228,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Dow Jones", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "152,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "the first three months of the year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "around 4.2%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Mark Zandi", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Moody's Analytics", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the week", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Zandi", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "less than 100,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "100,000", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "a tough day", "label": "DATE"}], "relevance_label": "short_term", "relevance_score": 0.9}
{"url": "https://www.cnbc.com/2025/04/30/gdp-q1-2025-.html", "title": "U.S. economy shrank 0.3% in the first quarter as Trump policy uncertainty weighed on businesses", "body": "watch now\n\nThe U.S. economy contracted in the first three months of 2025 on an import surge at the start of President Donald Trump's second term in office as he wages a potentially costly trade war. Gross domestic product, a sum of all the goods and services produced from January through March, fell at a 0.3% annualized pace, according to a Commerce Department report Wednesday adjusted for seasonal factors and inflation. This was the first quarter of negative growth since Q1 of 2022. Economists surveyed by Dow Jones had been looking for a gain of 0.4% after GDP rose by 2.4% in the fourth quarter of 2024. However, over the past day or so some Wall Street economists changed their outlook to negative growth, largely because of an unexpected rise in imports as companies and consumers sought to get ahead of the Trump tariffs implemented in early April. Indeed, imports soared 41.3% for the quarter, driven by a 50.9% increase in goods, for the biggest growth outside the Covid pandemic since 1974. Imports subtract from GDP, so the contraction in growth may not be viewed as negatively given the potential for the trend to reverse in subsequent quarters. Imports took more than 5 percentage points off the headline reading. Exports rose 1.8%. A slowdown in consumer spending and a sharp decline in federal outlays also contributed to the weak GDP number amid Elon Musk's efforts at the Department of Government Efficiency. \"Maybe some of this negativity is due to a rush to bring in imports before the tariffs go up, but there is simply no way for policy advisors to sugar-coat this. Growth has simply vanished,\" said Chris Rupkey, chief economist at Fwdbonds.\n\nPeople shop in a Manhattan store on July 27, 2023 in New York City. Spencer Platt | Getty Images News | Getty Images\n\nConsumer spending slowed during the period but was still positive. Personal consumption expenditures increased 1.8% for the period, the slowest quarterly gain since Q2 of 2023 and down from a 4% gain in the prior quarter. However, a separate report showed that spending was up 0.7% in March, higher than the 0.5% estimate. Moreover, private domestic investment soared during the period, rising 21.9%, primarily driven by a 22.5% surge in equipment spending that also could have been tariff driven. Federal government expenditures declined 5.1% for the quarter, shaving about one-third of a percentage point off GDP. The report comes ahead of the next uncertain steps for Trump's trade policy. In early April, the president announced 10% across-the-board tariffs on U.S. trade partners as well as a menu of select \"reciprocal\" duties against dozens of nations. On April 9, Trump suspended those duties for a 90-day negotiation period that has yet to yield results, though administration officials have indicated that some deals are near. \"No surprise that GDP took a hit in the first quarter, mainly because the balance of trade blew up as companies imported goods like crazy to front-run tariffs. The more telling number for the future of the expansion was consumer spending, and it grew, but at a relatively weak pace,\" said Robert Frick, corporate economist with Navy Federal Credit Union. \"That's concerning, but not alarming as it could have been due to bad weather and a spending surge at the end of last year.\" Stock market futures slipped following the report while Treasury yields moved higher. In a Truth Social post following the report, Trump did not address GDP specifically, instead referring to \"Biden's Stock Market, not Trump's.\" \"Tariffs will soon start kicking in, and companies are starting to move into the USA in record numbers,\" Trump wrote. \"Our Country will boom, but we have to get rid of the Biden 'Overhang.' This will take a while, has NOTHING TO DO WITH TARIFFS, only that he left us with bad numbers, but when the boom begins, it will be like no other. BE PATIENT!!!\"\n\nInflation higher", "publish_ts": 1745971200000, "source": "CNBC Economy", "entity_id": "Commerce Department", "sent_pos": 0.1259842813014984, "sent_neg": 0.8569898009300232, "ner_org": ["Commerce Department", "Dow Jones", "Trump", "the Department of Government Efficiency", "Fwdbonds", "Getty Images\n\nConsumer", "Trump", "Trump", "Navy Federal Credit Union", "Treasury", "Truth Social", "Biden's Stock Market"], "ner_gpe": ["U.S.", "Manhattan", "New York City", "U.S.", "USA"], "ner": ["Commerce Department", "Dow Jones", "U.S.", "Manhattan"], "topics": ["the", "for", "and", "trump", "that"], "_debug_sentiment_label": "negative", "_debug_ner_all": [{"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "the first three months of 2025", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Donald Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "second", "label": "ORDINAL"}, {"text": "January through March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "0.3%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Commerce Department", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Wednesday", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the first quarter", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Q1", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "Dow Jones", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "0.4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "2.4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the fourth quarter of 2024", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the past day", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "early April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "41.3%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the quarter", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "50.9%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Covid", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "1974", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "more than 5", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "1.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "Elon Musk's", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "the Department of Government Efficiency", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Chris Rupkey", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Fwdbonds", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Manhattan", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "July 27, 2023", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "New York City", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Spencer Platt", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Getty Images\n\nConsumer", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "1.8%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "quarterly", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Q2 of 2023", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "4%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the prior quarter", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "0.7%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "March", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "0.5%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "21.9%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "22.5%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "5.1%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "the quarter", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "about one-third", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "early April", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "10%", "label": "PERCENT"}, {"text": "U.S.", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "dozens", "label": "CARDINAL"}, {"text": "April 9", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "90-day", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "the first quarter", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Robert Frick", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Navy Federal Credit Union", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "the end of last year", "label": "DATE"}, {"text": "Treasury", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Truth Social", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Biden's Stock Market", "label": "ORG"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "USA", "label": "GPE"}, {"text": "Trump", "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Biden", "label": "PERSON"}], "relevance_label": "short_term", "relevance_score": 0.9}
